<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My blog</title>
    <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thetechartguy.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Planar Data Classification with One Hidden Layer</title>
      <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/deep-learning-week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thetechartguy.com/post/deep-learning-week3/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For Week 3 of the Deep Learning Specialization, we move beyond logistic regression and build our &lt;strong&gt;first neural network&lt;/strong&gt; — one with a single hidden layer. The task is to classify a toy &lt;strong&gt;flower-shaped dataset&lt;/strong&gt;, which logistic regression cannot handle well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Math to Code: Logistic Regression in Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/deep-learning-week1-and-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thetechartguy.com/post/deep-learning-week1-and-week2/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently taking &lt;strong&gt;Neural Networks and Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt; (part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/deep-learning&#34;&gt;Deep Learning Specialization on Coursera&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br&gt;
One of the first building blocks we meet is &lt;strong&gt;logistic regression&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training a Perceptron on Logical Operators</title>
      <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/perceptron-logical-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thetechartguy.com/post/perceptron-logical-operators/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the fundamental concepts in machine learning domain is the perceptron, an algorithm inspired by the functioning of a neuron. In this blog post, we will explore the intricacies of perceptron, understand how they learn, and delve into the practical aspect of training a perceptron on logical operators.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirror Controller Shapes Documentation</title>
      <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/mirror-controller-shape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thetechartguy.com/post/mirror-controller-shape/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you tired of manually repositioning asymmetrical components to match control curves on the opposite side in Maya? Look no further! Mirror Controller Shape is here to simplify your workflow and save you time. With just a few clicks, you can effortlessly mirror control shapes across different axes, ensuring symmetry and consistency in your projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm autocomplete setup for MotionBuilder scripting </title>
      <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/pycharm-motionbuilder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thetechartguy.com/post/pycharm-motionbuilder/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;PyCharm, a popular Python IDE, can greatly enhance your scripting experience in MotionBuilder. This tutorial will guide you through the process of configuring PyCharm for MotionBuilder scripting, enabling autocompletion feature to streamline your development workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duplicate objects along curve</title>
      <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/duplicate-along-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thetechartguy.com/post/duplicate-along-curve/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;big&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://thetechartguy.com/duplicateAlongCurve/duplicate_objects_along_curve_01.png&#34;
    alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;beads&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will describe how we can duplicate objects along a curve using Maya Mash.
For the Dora Milaje model, I had to place the beads on a leather jacket. After a bit of research I came to the conclusion that Maya Mash would be a good way of doing that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my Blog!!</title>
      <link>https://thetechartguy.com/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thetechartguy.com/post/welcome/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After more than a decade of immersing myself in the world of CG and gaming, I have finally made the decision to start my own blog. This space will serve as a platform for my personal growth, allowing me to make incremental changes and improvements every single day. Inspired by the timeless principle that &amp;ldquo;the best way to learn something is to teach it,&amp;rdquo; I aim to share my insights, observations, and experiences with the wider community. Join me on this exciting journey of exploration as I delve into industry trends, machine learning, art, games, characters, rigging, mathematics, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>